Inventory of Central Pacific Railroad Documents Collection MS 79 MS 79 MS 79
Test
Central Pacific Railroad Collection
1861-1959
Test
MS 79
388.5 Linear Feet 377 Boxes + 19 volumes
The Central Pacific Railroad Collection contains eights series filled with records from various departments within the Central Pacific from the mid nineteenth to the early twentieth century. The collection contains series on personnel, financial records, and documents from the Shop, Land, and Office of the Secretary, as well as tarriff waybills.
Conditions Governing Access
Some Restrictions apply. Contact Library Staff for details
Scope and Contents
¶ The Central Pacific Collection contains eight series of documents and files from various sectors of the Central Pacific Railroad Company. The earliest documents in this collection are dated 1861, while the latest go to 1959. Thus this collection represents nearly one-hundred years of railroad history. ¶
¶ The largest series in this collection are the financial records which span the length of the entire series (1861-1959). Notable financial records include the purchase of locomotives, rolling stock, equiptment, and building materials by C. P. Huntington for the company, as well as handwritten entries into the Huntington Cash Book giving intricate details of the purchases arranged in chronological order. There are two additional cash books that likewise contain handwritten entries, as well as newspaper and political clippings pertaining to events in Sacramento circa 1870. Finally, there is a collection of invoices, notes, and bills from vendors to the Central Pacific company from the 1860s and 1880s. ¶
¶ The next four series contain various documents and forms from the Land, Engineering, Equiptment, and Personnel sections of the Central Pacific. The Engineering series contains vouchers, invoices, inventory, and payroll ledgers for the department that detail what was purchased between 1862 and 1863, the list of employees and what they made during that same period, and an inventory of the shops in 1861 and 1873. The Personnel series consists entirely of payroll sheets from the Central Pacific Contruction Department (responsible for the actual building of the railroad), and includes handwritten details from Charles Crocker about the workers, their position, rate of pay, and total pay These records span from 1864 to 1866. Included in the writings are details on the Chinese gangs that worked seperately from the rest of the general labor force, and a single volume on unpaid wages from 1882-1885. The Eqiptment secion contains several boxes of specificaltions and schematics of various cars built and used by the Central Pacific between 1868 and 1929. Included are the schematics for passenger cars (1st class and coach), freight cars, and pieces of equiptment used to maintain them. ¶
¶ The Land Depatment series contains eight volumes of property books that detail all of the lands owned by the Central Pacific in Oregon, California, Nevada, and Utah between 1910 and 1949. There is additionally a three volume set of day books containing records of deeds, contracts, and cancellations from 1870 to 1883. Finally there is one volume containing station schematics from circa 1880. ¶
¶ The final three sections concern tariff forms, miscellaneous documents, and letters from the Office of the Secretary. The Tariff section contains samples of tariff forms for passenger and freight cars from the Central Pacific, as well as the Union Pacific railroad companies from 1875 to 1878. The miscellaneous series contains a litany of forms, including lists of tools on each locomotive, meteorlogical observation charts, and wage forms for personnel. The dates of the misc. section vary from the 1870s, through the early 1900s. The section concerning the Offic of the Secretary contains fifteen volumes that deal with bond records, mortgage rates, and coupons from 1899 to 1917. ¶
Central Pacific Railroad Company; Railroads--California--History
- Series 1: Financial Records, 1861-1959
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restrictions in place. Contact Library Staff for details
  Scope and Contents
  ¶ Early Central Pacific Railroad financial transactions were not divided by department. This Series includes company-wide transactions.¶
  ¶ Notable financial records cover purchases made for the company in New York by Collis P. Huntington for a period of over twenty years. Purchases include locomotives (including Central Pacific Railroad locomotive No. 1, "Gov. Stanford," and locomotive No. 3, "C. P. Huntington"), rolling stock, equipment components, construction equipment and supplies, and general stores. Handwritten entries in the C.P. Huntington cash books are arranged by month and contain the date purchased, name of the supplier, description of the material purchased, cost, shipping charges, and names and sailing dates of the vessels on which the merchandise was shipped to California. In later volumes transportation by rail is indicated. ¶
  ¶Two other early cash books, 1861-1870 and 1863-1869 also have extensive handwritten notes as well as newspaper clippings from Sacramento and other newspapers of the time affixed to the inside of the boards and to the end papers. In addition 1861-1870 has political handbills affixed to the end papers. ¶
  ¶ The Central Pacific Railroad vouchers comprise a key element in the California State Railroad Museum's Southern Pacific Railroad Company Records. They are among the earliest items in the collection. Some date prior to the incorporation of the Central Pacific. The early vouchers contain such information as payrolls for teams surveying the route across the Sierra Nevada, purchases of equipment for the surveys, and purchases of newspaper advertisements for the incorporation of the Central Pacific and for the initiation of construction. Later vouchers cover such items as the acquisition of equipment and supplies for building the railroad as well as for its early operation. Prominent individuals mentioned in the voucher collection include Theodore D. Judah, Leland Stanford, Charles Crocker, Mark Hopkins, Collis P. Huntington, and Alfred Hart. ¶
  ¶ The vouchers are arranged by year and then by voucher number (which results in rough chronological order). Each number series in parentheses equals one document box. ¶
  ¶ Notes and bills payable and receivable, 1863-1866 is a record book of notes and bills due to and payable by the Central Pacific Railroad for the period May 2, 1863 to September 1, 1866. Information may include date, drawer, payee, on what account, time, when due, amount and if paid. Includes records of short term notes drawn by the Central Pacific, Leland Stanford, and Collis P. Huntington. Also records interest payments by CP on bonds issued by the State of California. Sacramento County, and Placer County. ¶
  ¶ Invoices, September 1882- November 1883 contains invoices from vendors with corresponding Central Pacific expense bills, have been pasted into a scrapbook in roughly chronological order. There is a subject index at the beginning of the volume. Purchases cover a wide variety of products including materials for the construction of locomotives and rolling stock, fittings, waste, oil, lumber, glass, lanterns and drafting supplies as well as employee badges and tools. Selected companies include Westinghouse Air Brake, National Car Spring Company, Ensign Manufacturing Company, National Car Spring Company, John A. Roebling, Chicago Car Seal, and M. J. Goodenough, manufacturer of ostrich feather dusters. ¶
  Central Pacific Railroad Company; Railroads--California--History
  - Abstract of disbursements, [Volume] Jan. 1910 - Dec. 1911 (Box 299, Object 965)
  - Abstract of earnings and operating expenses
    - [Volume] 1864 - 1870 (Box 6)
    - [Volume] 1876 - 1879
    - [Volume] 1880 - 1882
    - [Volume] 1883 - 1885
  - Abstracts of cash disbursements, Sacramento Division, [Volume] Apr. - May 1912 (Box 208, Object 653)
  - Abstract of disbursements, [Volume] 1910-1912
  - Abstract of earnings and operating expenses, [Volume] 1876 - 1879
  - Accounts payable, 1, [Volume] Jul. 1900 - Apr. 1906 (Box 121, Object 312)
  - Accounts payable journal, [Volume] May 1906 - Jun. 1959 (Box 49, Object 109)
  - Balance sheet of general ledger
    - [Volume] 1910 - 1913 (Box 174, Object 771)
    - [Volume] Jun. 20, 1914 - Dec. 31, 1915 (Box 4, Object 20)
    - [Volume] Jan. 1916 - Dec. 1917 (Box 5, Object 21)
    - [Volume] Jan. 1918 - Dec. 1919 (Box 6, Object 22)
    - [Volume] Jan. 1920 - Dec. 1921 (Box 9, Object 23)
    - [Volume] Jan. 1922 - Dec. 1923 (Box 10, Object 24)
    - [Volume] Jan. 1924 - Dec. 1925 (Box 11, Object 25)
    - [Volume] Jan. - Dec. 1926 (Box 6, Object 26)
    - [Volume] Jan. 1927 - Dec. 1928 (Box 12, Object 27)
    - [Volume] Jan. 1929 - Dec. 1930 (Box 13, Object 28)
    - [Volume] Jan. 1931 - Dec. 1932 (Box 14, Object 29)
    - [Volume] Jan. 1933 - Dec. 1935 (Box 17, Object 30)
    - [Volume] Jan. 1948 - Dec. 1949 (Box 17, Object 31)
    - [Volume] Jan. - Dec. 1950 (Box 18, Object 32)
    - [Volume] Jan. 1953 - Dec. 1955 (Box 18, Object 33)
  - Car service balance, [Volume] Jan. 1923 - Oct. 1924 (Box 144, Object 489)
  - Cash books
    - [Volume] C. P. Huntington, New York, Jan. 1, 1865 - Dec. 31, 1870 (Box 4)
    - [Volume] C. P. Huntington, New York, Jun. 28, 1865 - Sep. 9, 1870 (Box 3)
    - [Volume] [General], May 1, 1861 - Oct. 29, 1864 (Box 1)
    - [Volume] 1, Apr. 1863 - Aug. 1869 (Box 7)
    - [Volume] General, Mar. - Jun. 1870
    - [Volume] 1; General, Jul. 1870 - Apr. 1873
    - [Volume] May - Nov. 1873
    - [Volume] Apr. 1906 - Jun. 1907 (Box 61, Object 179)
    - [Volume] 3, Jun. 1920 - Sep. 1928
    - [Volume] 4, Oct. 1928 - Sep. 1933
  - Cash book, Paymasters
    - [Volume] B, Jan. 3, 1871 - Jan. 31, 1873 (Box 5)
    - [Volume] D; Paymasters, Sep. 1875 - Nov. 1877
    - [Volume] E; 1877 - Jun. 1880
    - [Volume] F; Jul. 1880 - Aug. 1882
    - [Volume] G; Aug. 1882 - Jan. 1884
    - [Volume] H; Feb. 1884 - Sep. 1887
    - [Volume] I; Apr. 1885 - Mar. 1900
  - Cash book, Treasurers
    - [Volume] May 1, 1861 - Feb. 28, 1870 (Box 2)
    - [Volume] Jan. 2, 1877 - Oct. 31, 1878
    - [Volume] Nov. 1, 1878 - Mar. 31, 1881
    - [Volume] Apr. 1, 1881 - Sep. 29, 1883
    - [Volume] Oct. 1883 - Dec. 1890
    - [Volume] Jan. 1891 - Jul. 1899
    - [Volume] Jul. 1905 - Jun. 1920
    - [Volume] Feb. - Sep. 1915 (Box 137, Object 464)
    - [Volume] Oct. 1915 - May 1916 (Box 138, Object 477)
  - Cash book, Treasurer's memorandum
    - [Volume] 17, May 1924 - Jan. 1925 (Box 138, Object 476)
    - [Volume] 18, Jan. - Sep. 1925 (Box 138, Object 463)
    - [Volume] 22, Sep. 1927 - May 1928 (Box 138, Object 478)
  - [Volume] Cash book, un-mortgaged lands, Dec.1909 - Apr.1921 (Box 87, Object 255)
  - Cash disbursements, Sacramento Division
    - [Volume] Jun. 4, 1924 - Dec. 31, 1927 (Box 22, Object 40)
    - [Volume] Jan. - Mar. 1928 (Box 212, Object 659)
    - [Volume] Apr. - Jun. 1928 (Box 214, Object 661)
    - [Volume] Oct. - Dec. 1928 (Box 210, Object 656)
    - [Volume] Jan. - Mar. 1929 (Box 213, Object 660)
    - [Volume] Jun. 1929 (Box 198, Object 652)
    - [Volume] Jul. - Sep. 1929 (Box 212, Object 662)
    - [Volume] Dec. 1929 (Box 208, Object 654)
  - Cash receipts
    - [Volume] Apr. 1906 - Apr. 1917
    - [Volume] Jan. 2, 1919 - May 16, 1924 (Box 21, Object 39)
    - [Volume] Jan. 3, 1925 - Dec. 31, 1927 (Box 20, Object 37)
    - [Volume] Jan. 2, 1929 - Dec. 31, 1931 (Box 20, Object 38)
  - Cash receipts, Operating Department
    - [Volume] Jan. - Dec. 1872
    - [Volume] Aug. 1874 - May 1875
    - [Volume] Oct. 1876 - May 1877
    - [Volume] Jun. - Dec. 1877
    - [Volume] Jan. - Aug. 1878
    - [Volume] Apr. - Dec. 1879
    - [Volume] Aug. 1880 - Mar. 1881
    - [Volume] Mar. - Oct. 1881
    - [Volume] Oct. 1881 - May 1882
    - [Volume] May - Nov. 1882
    - [Volume] Nov. 1882 - May 1883
    - [Volume] Nov. 1883 - May 1884
    - [Volume] May - Oct. 1884
    - [Volume] Oct. 1884 - Apr. 1885
    - [Volume] Apr. 1885 - Mar. 1893
    - [Volume] Apr. 1885 - Nov. 1888
  - Commissary stock ledger, [Volume] Jan. 1907 - Sep. 1910 (Box 143, Object 480)
  - Employees service and compensation cumulating sheet, Sacramento division [Volume] Mar. 1930 (Box 215, Object 664)
  - Expense vouchers, [Volume] Mar. - Nov. 1907 (Box 253, Object 792)
  - Foreign roads passenger corporate ledger, ticket balance, [Volume] Jan. - Dec. 1920 (Box 131, Object 488)
  - [Volume] Invoices, [Volume] Sep. 1882 – Nov. 1883
  - Invoices, miscellaneous [Volume]
  - Journals
    - [Volume] Aug. 1869-Apr. 1876 (Box 7)
    - [Volume] May 1876-Dec. 1882 (Box 8)
    - [Volume] Dec. 1882-May 1885 (Box 8)
    - [Volume] Oct. 1906 - Apr. 1909 (Box 65, Object 190)
    - [Volume] Jun. - Dec. 1907 (Box 54, Object 136)
    - [Volume] Feb. - Sep. 1908 (Box 79, Object 206)
    - [Volume] Jun. - Oct. 1911 (Box 79, Object 227)
    - [Volume] 1916 (Box 52, Object 137)
    - [Volume] Federal, 1919 (Box 61, Object 191)
    - [Volume] Federal, 1920 (Box 62, Object 185)
    - [Volume] 1922 - 1922 (Box 58, Object 142)
    - [Volume] 1926 (Box 55, Object 156)
  - Journal, Railway clubs II, [Volume] Jul. 1913 - Jun. 1915 (Box 143, Object 485)
  - Journal, Steamship, [Volume] Jan. 1913 - Nov. 1919 (Box 76, Object 224)
  - Labor distribution sheet / distribution of labor, bridge and building department, Sacramento division
    - [Volume] Aug. - Sep. 1912 (Box 210, Object 658)
    - [Volume] Oct. 1912 (Box 214, Object 663)
    - [Volume] Jan. - Feb. 1913 (Box 211, Object 657)
    - [Volume] Jul. 1928 - Sep. 1928 (Box 249, Object 775)
  - Ledgers
    - C, 3, [Volume] Jul. 1894 - Jun. 1897 (Box 74, Object 213)
    - [Volume] Jun. 30 1905 - Mar. 31 1921
    - [Volume] 1917 (Box 61, Object 188)
    - [Volume] Jan. 1918 - Dec. 1923 (Box 67, Object 192)
    - E, [Volume] 1925 - 1932
    - F, [Volume] Dec. 31, 1932 - Dec. 31, 1944
    - Time vouchers ledger, 1, [Volume] May 1906 - Oct. 1909 (Box 55, Object 141)
  - [Volume] Materials and supply account book, 1866-1875 (Box 6)
  - [Volume] Notes and bills payable and receivable, 1863-1866
  - Receipts
    - 2, 1455 to 2921, [Volume] Dec. 1910 - Apr. 1912 (Box 141, Object 461)
    - Nos. 222 to 5313, [Volume] Apr. 1912 - Oct. 1913 (Box 141, Object 460)
  - Register of bills collectible, [Volume] Jun. 1921 - Oct. 1924 (Box 62, Object 181)
  - Report of the Central Pacific Railroad to the auditor of railroad accounts, Washington, D.C.
    - [Volume] for the half-year ending December 31, 1877; June 30, 1878; December 31, 1878; June 30, 1879; December 31, 1879; June 30, 1880; December 31, 1880; June 30, 1881
    - Report of the Central Pacific Railroad Company to the Commissioner of Railroads, Department of the Interior, Washington, D.C.
    - [Volume] for the half-year ending December 31, 1881; June 30, 1882; December 31, 1882; June 30, 1883; December 31, 1883; June 30, 1884; December 31, 1884; June 30, 1885; December 31, 1885
    - [Volume] for the half-year ending June 30, 1886; December 31, 1886; June 30, 1887; December 31, 1887; June 30, 1888; December 31, 1888; June 30, 1889; December 30, 1889
    - [Volume] for the half-year ending June 30, 1890; December 31, 1890; June 30, 1891; December 31, 1891; June 30, 1892; December 31, 1892; June 30, 1893
    - [Volume] for the year ending June 30, 1894; June 30, 1895; June 30, 1896; June 30, 1897; June 30, 1898; June 30, 1899; June 30, 1900; June 30, 1901; June 30; 1902; June 30, 1903; June 30, 1904
  - Rolling stock return & addition & betterments to equipment
    - [Volume] 1925
    - [Volume] 1926 (Box 347, Object 2568)
    - [Volume] 1926 (Box 344, Object 2573)
    - [Volume] 1927 (Box 345, Object 2577)
    - [Volume] 1928 (Box 346, Object 2567)
    - [Volume] 1928 (Box 246, Object 2575)
    - [Volume] 1929 (Box 344, Object 2574)
    - [Volume] 1931 (Box 342, Object 2569)
  - Statement of expenditures
    - [Volume] Jul. 1, 1908 - May 31, 1925 (Box 5, Object 18)
    - [Volume] 1923 - 1924 (Box 4, Object 19)
  - Tax journals
    - In San Francisco cities and towns
      - [Volume] 1906 (Box 62, Object 183)
      - [Volume] 1907 (Box 48, Object 144)
      - [Volume] 1909 (Box 39, Object 127)
      - [Volume] 1911 (Box 53, Object 158)
    - Non-operative cities and towns, [Volume] 1911 (Box 57, Object 150)
    - In counties in California, Nevada, Utah, Arizona, and New Mexico
      - [Volume] 1906 (Box 66, Object 148)
      - [Volume] 1908 (Box 47, Object 128)
      - [Volume] 1909 (Box 39, Object 126)
      - [Volume] 1910 (Box 48, Object 145)
      - [Volume] 1911 (Box 57, Object 149)
      - [Volume] 1912 (Box 47, Object 147)
    - Non-operative counties
      - [Volume] 1911 (Box 54, Object 131)
      - [Volume] 1917 (Box 40, Object 134)
      - [Volume] 1919 (Box 61, Object 189)
      - [Volume] 1920 (Box 62, Object 186)
      - [Volume] 1921 (Box 48, Object 143)
      - [Volume] 1923 (Box 58, Object 151)
      - [Volume] 1924 (Box 55, Object 157)
      - [Volume] 1925 (Box 48, Object 146)
      - [Volume] 1926 (Box 56, Object 154)
      - [Volume] 1927 (Box 56, Object 153)
      - [Volume] 1928 (Box 55, Object 155)
    - Operative counties
      - [Volume] 1913 (Box 47, Object 135)
      - [Volume] 1914 (Box 39, Object 130)
      - [Volume] 1915 - 1916 (Box 53, Object 124)
      - [Volume] 1921 (Box 40, Object 132)
      - [Volume] 1922 (Box 40, Object 129)
      - [Volume] 1923 (Box 52, Object 140)
      - [Volume] 1924 (Box 52, Object 139)
      - [Volume] 1925 (Box 52, Object 138)
      - [Volume] 1927 (Box 40, Object 133)
      - [Volume] 1928 (Box 56, Object 152)
  - Trial balances, [Volume] Jun. 1902 - Jun. 1904 (Box 131, Object 487)
  - Vouchers
    - 1861 - 1871
    - 1871 - 1877
    - 1877 - 1892
  - Fragile
    - 1893 - 1898
    - 1898 - 1907, 1910
  - Waybills, Carson, Nevada
    - Jan. 1878 - Feb. 1878 (Box 237, Object 726)
    - Feb. 1878 - Mar. 1878 (Box 236, Object 725)
    - Apr. 1878 (Box 242, Object 739)
    - May. 1878 (Box 235, Object 721)
    - Jul. 1878 (Box 237, Object 727)
    - Oct. 1878 - Nov. 1878 (Box 232, Object 722)
    - Nov. 1878 - Dec. 1878 (Box 232, Object 723)
    - Feb. 1879 (Box 233, Object 720)
    - Feb. 1879 - Mar. 1879 (Box 236, Object 724)
    - Aug. 1879 (Box 234, Object 718)
    - Feb. 1880 - Mar. 1880 (Box 231, Object 714)
    - Feb. 1880 - Mar. 1880 (Box 234, Object 717)
    - May. 1880 - Jun. 1880 (Box 231, Object 715)
    - Jun. 1880 - Jul. 1880 (Box 233, Object 719)
    - Aug. 1880 - Sep. 1880 (Box 235, Object 716)
- Series 2: Engineering Department Records, 1861-1873; 2.5 Linear Feet 2 Boxes. 1 Volume
  Restrictions in place. Contact Library Staff for details.
  ¶ This series contains invoice, payroll, and inventory papers from the Central Pacific Engineering Department seperated into two boxes and one volume binder. The invoice box contains information such as vendor name, date of invoice, description and amount of payment organized chronologically from 1861 to 1863. ¶
  ¶ Monthly payroll information, including employee name, occupation, dates of employment, rate of pay, monies owed, and signature of employee indicating receipt of pay. Job classifications include engineer, leveler, flagman, transit man, rodman, chainman, teamster, axeman, draughtsman, office assistant and copyist. Many of the payrolls bear the signatures of noted figures: Theodore Dehone Judah (1826-1863), George Henry Goddard (1817-1906), (government surveyor and artist) and Samuel Skerry Montague. ¶
  ¶ Finally, the inventory selection includes a descriptive inventory of physical characteristics at principal facilities. Completeness of information under each category varies, but may include elevation, date laid out, distance from end point, engineering station numbers, dimensions of structures, costs, construction dates. A Southern Pacific R[esearch] T[eam]. The inventoried sites include the Central Pacific Yard at Ogden, UT, the Oregon Branch, and various facilities in Northern and Central California. Inventories sheets are dates between 1861 and 1873. ¶
  - Subseries 1: Invoices and Vouchers
    - August 31, 1862. Hodge & Wood (San Francisco), August 28, 1862, stationery $96.75 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - September 1862. George H. Goddard, September 4-29, trip from Sacramento to Perkins and return $246 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - September 30, 1862. Theodore D. Judah, September 25, 1862, Feather River reconnaissance (September 5-18). Signed by T. D. Judah. $259.15 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - September 30, 1862. Lawrence & Houseworth (San Francisco), September 1, 1862, surveying instruments + n.d., surveying equipment $67 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - September 30, 1862. E. M. Skaggs (Sacramento), August 30, 1862, hiring of horses $5.00 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - September 30, 1862. Thomas Tennant (San Francisco), September 25, 1862, surveying instruments. Signed by T. D. Judah. $50 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - October 31, 1862. J. Armstrong & Company, October 1, 1862, hiring of horses by Taylor, Goddard from Daniel W. Strong, Dutch Flat, railroad reconnaisance. Signed by T. D. Judah. $20 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - October 31, 1862. Thomas Morris, October 10, 1862, hiring of horses, railroad reconnaissance by Goddard and Taylor, Dutch Flat. Signed by T.D. Judah. $15 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - December 15, 1862. Edward D. Judah, miscellaneous dates, November and December 1862, miscellaneous expenses, locating party, L. F. Ha[n]ford, William Reynolds, John Ziegenbein, A. T. Nelson (Sacramento), $92.14 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - December 31, 1862. George H. Goddard, November and December 1862, survey party expenses, from T. E. Stephens (Auburn), C. M. Silva (Auburn), Smith & Hubbell (Smithville). $112.57. (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - December 31, 1862. P. S. Hickman, December 8, 1862, Sacramento Bee. Signed by T.D. Judah. $1.50 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Dec. 31, 1862. Samuel S. Montague, December 28, 1862, expenses of locating party. Signed by Samuel S. Montague. $28.43 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - December 31, 1862. C. M. Silva (Auburn), December 13, 1862, bill of provisions for s[urveying?] party, signed by T. D. Judah. $1.75 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - January 31, 1863. H. L. Hall, expenses of location party, December 1862 - January 1863, vendors include H. L. Hall, Peter Harrison (Auburn), George H. Stephens (Auburn), Office Stage Company (Auburn), E. Beekly (Auburn), G. H. Merrill (Mountaineer House), Joseph Harris (Neilsburgh), J. B. Stanton. $316.26 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - January 31, 1863. Samuel S. Montague, not dated, expenses of surveying party, vendors include John Ziegenbein, Thomas Haskell, E. W. Sherman. Signed by S. S. Montague. $237.62 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - March 11, 1863. Samuel S. Montague, February and March, 1863, expenses of surveying party, vendors include A. A. Durfee (Folsom), John Liegenbein (Lincoln), W. L. Perkins (Auburn), C. M. Silva. L. D. Merrick (?) (Lincoln). $228.37 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - March 31, 1863. H. L. Hall, January 26 - April 2, 1863, expenses of locating party, February and March 1863. $527.92 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Mar. 31, 1863. Samuel S. Montague, March 14, 1863, supplies and surveying equipment. $15.00 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Subseries 2: Payroll
    - November 1862 George Henry Goddard party (1) (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - December 1862 George Henry Goddard party; Edward D. Judah party; Samuel Skerry Montague and Edward D. Judah party; At Sacramento (4) (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - January 1863 H. L. (?) Hall party; Samuel Skerry Montague party; [At Sacramento] (3) (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - February 1863 H. L. (?) Hall party; Samuel Skerry Montague party; [At Sacramento] (3) (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - March 1863 H. L. (?) Hall party; Samuel Skerry Montague party; [At Sacramento] (3) (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 3: Inventory
    - [Volume] 1861/1873 (Box 3)
- Series 3: Land Department Records, 1870-1949; 12 Volumes